<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xcode on Andy Ibanez</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/tags/xcode/</link><description>Recent content in Xcode on Andy Ibanez</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.andyibanez.com/tags/xcode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>JavaScriptCore and Swift</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/javascriptcore-and-swift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/javascriptcore-and-swift/</guid><description>&lt;p>JavaScriptCore and Swift&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless how you feel about JavaScript as a programming language, there is one simple fact: JavaScript is pretty ubiquitous, and its uses have expanded beyond web scripting. It has become a pretty popular language for a vast array of domains. For this reason, making languages interoperate with it is pretty important, and both Swift and Objective-C are no exception. We can work with JavaScript, not only by executing JavaScript code directly from our Swift code, but we can even expose code from Swift and Objective-C to JavaScript. That&amp;rsquo;s how important this language is, and these features open a world of possibilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Xcode New File Templates</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/xcode-new-file-templates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/xcode-new-file-templates/</guid><description>&lt;p>As you work on projects, you may notice that there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that can be really improved: Creating new files. Every single developer has gone to the &lt;code>File &amp;gt; New File&lt;/code> screen on Xcode to create files before. Whether to create new view controllers, data models, or whatever else, it is one of the most common places you may use in your day to day life as an iOS developers.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>