<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andy Ibanez</title>
    <link>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andy Ibanez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 14:47:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the NSOperation APIs for Apple&#39;s Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/exploring-the-nsoperation-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 14:47:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/exploring-the-nsoperation-apis/</guid>
      <description>The original title for this article was posted on my old website in 2012 and it was titled &amp;ldquo;Multithreading on iOS And Mac OS X Using NSOperations&amp;rdquo;. The original examples were written in Objective-C. This article has been rewritten from scratch not only to give the examples in Swift, but also to improve the quality of the old article. It has been shortened, and both language and tone have been revised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rclone: From Basics to Encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/rclone-basics-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 13:59:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/posts/rclone-basics-encryption/</guid>
      <description>The original version of this article was titled &amp;ldquo;rclone and Encryption Tutorial&amp;rdquo; and was posted in the old version of my website. The original article was written in February 2017 for a much older version of rclone. This revised article covers rclone 1.48, and it has been rewritten from scratch to improve its quality. The examples used in the original article have been kept.
rclone is a command line tool, similar to rsync, with the difference that it can sync, move, copy, and in general do other file operations on cloud storage services, such as Dropbox and Google Drive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>