<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source on Andy Ibanez</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source on Andy Ibanez</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:27:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.andyibanez.com/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AIiCloudSync</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/aiicloudsync/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:27:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/aiicloudsync/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/AndyIbanez/AIiCloudSync">GitHub Repository&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="aiicloudsync">AIiCloudSync&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>AIiCloudSync is a simple Package written in Swift to synchronize specific UserDefaults with the iCloud Key Value store (&lt;code>NSUbiquitousKeyValueStore&lt;/code>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To use this package, create a single instance of &lt;code>AIiCloudSync&lt;/code>, and keep a reference to it. Once you create it, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about it any longer. It will automatically sync changes between iCloud and your local UserDefaults through the lifetime of your application. You can optionally receive notifications when the iCloud Syncs change so you can react accordingly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fsduplicates</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/fsduplicates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 19:49:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/fsduplicates/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/fsduplicates.png" alt="fsduplicates">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2016&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Command line tool to detect duplicate songs in OS X/macOS based on their Audio Fingerprints.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>fsduplicates helps you find song duplicates recursively in any specific directory and output its findings in a different directory. With the generated results you can later analyse and take action on duplicate songs. The results are in plain text files, which you can analyse using any tool, like Unix standard commands, or fsduplicates’ tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leopaster</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/leopaster/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/leopaster/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/leopaster.png" alt="Leopaster">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2015&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quick Status Bar Menu on OS X that allows you to quickly paste code on @DHowett’s ghostbin.com.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ghostbin.com is a simple pasteboard service that allows people to paste code or any other text and to quickly share a link to them. These services allow developers to share code snippets faster to either request help with an specific piece of code, or to help others with theirs (Other uses may apply).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cecrecy</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/cecrecy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/cecrecy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/cecrecy.png" alt="Cecrecy">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2013.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to protect app data from your friends or family that are constantly asking for your iDevice, there are a couple of things you can do: You can tell them not to enter certain apps, empowering their curiosity and therefore exposing your private data, or you can passcode-lock certain apps, which if they see, they will just wonder what you’re hiding that they can’t see.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maulencer</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/maulencer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 21:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/maulencer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/maulencer.png" alt="Maulencer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2013.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A friend of mine had his hardware ringer of his phone die on him. Because of that, toggling the ringer on and off was quite a chore for him. Without installing SBSettings or anything equivalent to that, he had to go to the settings app and toggle the ringer on and off there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So he asked me to write an icon on SpringBoard that would toggle the ringer. And here it is. It’s a really, really simple tweak. In developer circles it probably isn’t worth anyone’s time. But anyway, I decided to release to the public and here it is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sideswitch Toggles</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/sideswitch-toggles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 21:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/sideswitch-toggles/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/sideswitch-toggles.png" alt="Sideswitch Toggles">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2012.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sideswitch Toggles is a MobileSubstrate tweak that gives you full control over your iPhone’s Ringer (and as such, it isn’t available for the iPod Touch). The tweak simply modifies the action that happens when you toggle the ringer on and off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, Sideswitch Toggles comes with the ability to toggle Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, Airplane Mode, and Do Not Disturb. The capabilities of Sideswitch can be easily extended by other developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Silight</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/silight/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 21:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/silight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/silight.png" alt="SiLight">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2011&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SiLight is a small AssistantExtension that allows Siri to turn on your phone’s torch to use it as a flashlight. SiLight is a real quick flashlight, since commands work in the Lockscreen too. SiLight was programmed having natural speech in mind, instead of talking to her like a robot (“flashlight on”) you can ask her as you would ask anyone (“I need a flashlight”, “Siri, there’s a blackout”). It also features some hidden surprises for geeks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Combox</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/combox/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 18:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/combox/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/combox.png" alt="Combox">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2012.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Combox is a third-party client for Dropbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you love Dropbox? Dropbox is a very nifty service that allows you to store your files in the cloud. With Dropbox, you can upload and download your documents and photos anywhere, any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why a third-party client? This app was made with Dropbox lovers and Power Users in mind. It offers many features that no other Dropbox clients for iOS offer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>