<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>App Store on Andy Ibanez</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/tags/app-store/</link><description>Recent content in App Store on Andy Ibanez</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 21:06:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.andyibanez.com/tags/app-store/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Next Anime Episode</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/nextanimeepisode1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 21:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/nextanimeepisode1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="important-note">IMPORTANT NOTE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>While I am the original developer of this app, it has since been transferred to &lt;a href="https://www.alonwaller.com">Alon Waller&lt;/a>, so I can no longer offer support for the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/nextanimeepisode1.png" alt="Next Anime Episode 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/next-anime-episode/id1227965532">Download on the App Store&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://www.andyibanez.com/privacy-policies/nae1">Privacy Policy&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next Anime Episode does one job: To help you keep track of airing anime and when they will have a new episode available in Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally, sub based simulcast streaming services have the newest episodes available within one hour after they air in Japan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mignori 1</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/mignori1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 17:17:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/mignori1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/mignori1.png" alt="Mignori 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project, but a new version is in the works. Developed in 2014.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mignori is a mobile client to use with -booru or -booru based sites (Gelbooru and Danbooru, to name a few).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A -booru imageboard is simply a board where people post pictures and tag with them relevant attributes. This allows other users to search for images in these boards and find images with the qualities they’re looking for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Combox</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/combox/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 18:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/combox/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/combox.png" alt="Combox">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2012.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Combox is a third-party client for Dropbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you love Dropbox? Dropbox is a very nifty service that allows you to store your files in the cloud. With Dropbox, you can upload and download your documents and photos anywhere, any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why a third-party client? This app was made with Dropbox lovers and Power Users in mind. It offers many features that no other Dropbox clients for iOS offer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBConverter</title><link>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/sb-converter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 18:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.andyibanez.com/projects/sb-converter/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.andyibanez.com/img/sb-converter.png" alt="SB Converter">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Discontinued project. Developed in 2011.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A very complete base number converter for programmers and computer science students.
Super Base Converter (SBConverter) is a very powerful base number conversion tool. It offers a simple and intuitive user interface free of distractions to allow users to quickly convert from one number base to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Convert any number back and forth in any base from base 2 (binary) to base 16 (hexadecimal).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Convert any number base up to base 64 (no support to convert numbers in base 17 or longer to any other base, sorry! But you can convert any number to these high bases).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fast and slick user interface: Transform any number to any base as you type it instead of tapping a “convert” button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change number bases easily.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="changelog">Changelog:&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="10">1.0&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Initial Release.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>